

Rua Ceará, 353 Divinópolis, MG Brazil

□ (+55) 31 99357-7061 | 🗷 luiz@luizcorreia.eti.br | 🏕 www.luizcorreia.eti.br | 🖸 luizcorreia | 🛅 luizgcorreia

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

Current Backend Engineer at start-up company Rethink.

10+ years experience specializing in civil engineering analysis software, embedded systems, backend development, infrastructure automation, and computer security

Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

I believe that creative technologies are indistinguishable from works of art.

Education

Estácio de Sá Divinópolis, Brazil

BTECH. IN SYSTEM ANALYSIS 2015 - 2019

• Half graduation executed on Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais

Skills_

DevOps AWS, IaC, CI/CD, Jenkins, Sonar, Github Back-end Express.is, Diango, .NET Core, REST API Front-end Redux, React, GatsbyJS, HTML5, LESS, SASS Programming Node.js, Rust, Python, C/C++, C#, LaTeX

Languages Portuguese, English

Experience

Rethink/Smiles Minas Gerais, Brazil

BACKEND ENGINEER

Nov 2020 - Present

Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2020

- Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of micro-services architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js and in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Deployed a centralized logging environment(ELK, CloudWatch, AWS X-Ray) which gather log data from lambdas and AWS resources.
- Designed the Smiles Frump, a simple node is lib that automatically captures unhandled errors thrown by lambda functions and formats output response based on a defined schema.
- · Designed a nodejs module that mask sensitive information from given JSON (objects / arrays) using functional programming style, and pure functions.

Meu Locker Minas Gerais, Brazil

FULL STACK DEVELOPER • Implemented RESTful API server for locker booking application (Meu Locker in Google Play).

- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, CircleCI, and several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, Redis, Lambda, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway) companies in Brazil.

Meatballs Digital Brunch Minas Gerais, Brazil ENTREMETIER DEVELOPER Jan. 2010 - Present

Full Stack developer, building and creating awesome things, Meat-balls is a kitchen of ideas where the ingredients are art and tech-nology.

- Build hardware and software integrations to give live to a bunch of experiences.
- · Consulting in the development of automation systems and embed- ded systems, microcontroller programming and development of manmachine interface.
- Projects: Unimed Juntos Inovamos, Interactive Smell System Tools, artReality

Strata Engenharia Minas Gerais, Brazil

System Analyst Developer

Jul. 2011 - Out. 2014

• Designed the AMS(Automated Maker System), an automated sys- tem that marks the road with pre-programmed spacing (or stak- ing) by painting the lane; with paint road marking automatically in two colours, while the vehicle is in motion. The system is based on a mechanical-hydraulic assembly that shoots ink on the pavement based on the DMI.

- Implemented computing algorithms in a C# to analyse road sur- veys, like FWD (Falling Weight Deflectometer), IRI (International Roughness Index), Visual Condition Surveys.
- Designed the hardware and the software from the MCSS (Multi Cam Survey System), a vision system based on high-resolution cameras, digital odometer (Encoder), Aided GPS (INS) and barometer. The design has three main objectives: high resolution; high-quality im- ages at highway speed by controlling exposure value and shutter, precise positioning, and triggering intervals through independent triggering channels; and various image formats at the same high resolution.
- Designed a unified platform to get information from sensors like GPS, INS, encoder, barometer, etc. Using a fast, secure and struc-tured protocol.

Extracurricular Activity

Comunidade Servos da Cruz Minas Gerais

VOLUNTIER

Sep. 2016 - PRESENT

• Designed a tech lab, enable digital access, and provide education to create a community that empowers people to realize their potential.

- Provided technical support for Linux/Windows hardware and software.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

Amigos da Cultura Minas Gerais

 CORE MEMBER
 Jan. 2003 - Dez. 2005

• With the Arte Solidária project, a show was created in which the whole community was called to participate, with which we created and discovered talents. All income from the event was converted to institutions that support society and nonprofits.

Certifications

2020AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate,AWS2020AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner,AWS2012MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional,Microsoft2012MTA: Software Development Fundamentals,Microsoft